{"name": "58E  2001-12", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. If 3x = 81, then x = ?", "choices": {"A": " 3", "B": " 4", "C": " 5", "D": " 8", "E": " 27"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. Two lines intersect at an angle of 89\u00b0, as shown below. What is the measure of the angle indicated with a question mark?", "choices": {"A": " 1\u00b0", "B": " 89\u00b0", "C": " 90\u00b0", "D": " 91\u00b0", "E": " Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3.  In \u0394ABC, the sum of the measures of \u2220A and \u2220B is 68\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220C?", "choices": {"A": " 44\u00b0", "B": " 68\u00b0", "C": " 112\u00b0", "D": " 122\u00b0", "E": " 136\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4.  What is the value of 3x2 - 5x when x = -2?", "choices": {"A": " -14", "B": " -2", "C": " 2", "D": " 5", "E": " 22"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5.  On a particular road map,  inch represents 18 miles. About how many miles apart are 2 towns that are  inches apart on this map?", "choices": {"A": " 18", "B": " ", "C": " 36", "D": " 45", "E": " 90"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6.  If a, b, c, and d are any 4 integers, then a + b + c = a + c + d is true only if which of the following is true?", "choices": {"A": " d = b", "B": " c = a", "C": " c = b", "D": " c = d", "E": " a = d"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7.  Suppose that replacing an old electric water heater with a new, energy-efficient electric water heater will reduce a home's average monthly electric bill by 20%. If the old electric water heater in a home with a current average monthly electric bill of $110 is replaced by anew energy-efficient one, what will be the home's new average monthly electric bill?", "choices": {"A": " $22.00", "B": " $88.00", "C": " $90.00", "D": " $104.50", "E": " $109.80"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8.  How many bottles can be filled with 0.35 ounces of perfume each, using 41.5 ounces of perfume?", "choices": {"A": " 12", "B": " 14", "C": " 15", "D": " 118", "E": " 119"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9.  You have agreed with an automobile dealership to purchase a car for $3,400, which includes tax and all miscellaneous costs. You give the dealership $400 as a down payment and get a car loan for the rest. If you pay off your loan by making 24 monthly payments of\uff04150 each, the total of all your payments will be how much more than the actual purchase price of the car?", "choices": {"A": " $200", "B": " $600", "C": " $3,000", "D": " $3,600", "E": " $4,000"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10.  The monthly rents for single rooms at 5 colleges are\uff04350, $310, $360, $320, and $310, respectively. What is the mean of these monthly rents?", "choices": {"A": "$310", "B": "$320", "C": "$330", "D": "$335", "E": "$360"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11.  What is the value of 2|4 - 13| - 3(5 + 2) ?", "choices": {"A": " -39", "B": " -35", "C": " -27", "D": " -26", "E": " -3"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12.  If 9m + 57 = 87, then 9(m + 6) =?", "choices": {"A": " 36", "B": " 66", "C": " 84", "D": " 93", "E": " 141"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13.  If identical cylindrical cans are packed 12 cans to an 18\u201d x 24\" rectangular carton, as shown below, what is the approximate radius, in inches, of each of the cans?", "choices": {"A": " 2", "B": " 3", "C": " 12", "D": " 6\u03c0", "E": " 8\u03c0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14.  Points A, B, C, and D are collinear such that A is between C and B, and D is between A and B. Which of the following statements about the distances between these points must be true?", "choices": {"A": " AB + BC = AC", "B": " BA + AD = BD", "C": " BC + CD = BC", "D": " CA + AD = CD", "E": " CB + BD = CD"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. The power that a hydroelectric dam generates can be modeled using the formulawhere P is the power the dam generates, in megawatts; Q is the flow rate of the river, in cubic meters per second; h is the height of the dam, in meters; and \u03b3 is the weight per unit volume of water, in newtons per cubic meter. According to this model, which of the following is closest to the power, in megawatts, generated by a dam that is 25 meters high if the flow rate is 8.0 cubic meters per second and the weight of water is 9,790 newtons per cubic meter?", "choices": {"A": " 0.18", "B": " 0.20", "C": " 1.8", "D": " 2.0", "E": " 4.0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. Kay collected data from 5 friends who have jobs. She plotted the data on a graph to compare the number of hours her friends worked to their total earnings in dollars, as shown below. According to the graph, which of her 5 friends earned the most per hour?", "choices": {"A": " Ana", "B": " Bonita", "C": " Chen", "D": " Damian", "E": " Evan"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17.  On the lot at Quality Used Cars, there are only 15 cars with automatic transmission and only 12 cars with bucket seats. The number of cars on the lot with both automatic transmission and bucket seats is:", "choices": {"A": " exactly 27.", "B": " exactly 3.", "C": " at least 3.", "D": " no more than 3.", "E": " no more than 12."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18.  Which of the following describes the solutions to the equation x2 - 8x - 48 = 0?", "choices": {"A": " 2 negative numbers", "B": " 2 positive numbers", "C": " 1 negative number and 1 positive number", "D": " 1 real number and 1 imaginary number", "E": " 2 imaginary numbers"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19.  Lee walked for 20 minutes on a motorized treadmill that was set at a constant speed of 4 miles per hour. About how many miles did Lee walk on the treadmill?", "choices": {"A": " Between  and 1", "B": " Between 1 and ", "C": " Between  and 2", "D": " Between 2 and ", "E": " More than "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20.  In the figure below, P is on AB, and E is on PD. Polygon ABCDEF, with dimensions in inches as marked, has an area of 122 square inches. What is the area of \u0394PEB, in square inches?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " 6", "C": " 12", "D": " ", "E": " 15"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21.  (3xy + 21xy2 - 7y) - (5xy + 12xy2 - 3y) is equivalent to: ", "choices": {"A": " -8xy + 9xy2 - 4y", "B": " -8xy + 33xy2 - 10y", "C": " -2xy + 9xy2 - 4y", "D": " -2xy + 9xy2 - 10y", "E": " -2xy + 33xy2 - 10y"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22.  Chase City is 12 miles directly east of Red Oak, and Wylliesburg is 8 miles directly north of Red Oak. If you could travel in a straight line from Wylliesburg directly to Chase City, about how many miles would you travel?", "choices": {"A": " 10", "B": " 14", "C": " 16", "D": " 18", "E": " 20"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23.  In which of the following are , , and  arranged in ascending order?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24.  The area of an ellipse may be found by using the expression \u03c0ab, where a is  the length of the major axis and b is  the length of the minor axis. What is the area, in square units, of the largest ellipse that can be inscribed in a rectangle with length 10 units and width 6 units?", "choices": {"A": " 6\u03c0", "B": " 10\u03c0", "C": " 15\u03c0", "D": " 30\u03c0", "E": " 34\u03c0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25.  If , then x =?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26.  Erin had 6 slips of paper, numbered 1 through 6. Erik renumbers them once by adding 3 to each odd number and subtracting 1 from each even number. When 2 renumbered slips of paper are chosen at random, what is the highest sum possible?", "choices": {"A": " 11", "B": " 13", "C": " 14", "D": " 16", "E": " 17"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27.  Water drips from 2 faucets at different rates. The first faucet drips 1 drop every 12 seconds, and the second faucet drips 1 drop every 18 seconds. If you see these faucets drip simultaneously, the next time they drip simultaneously will be in how many seconds?", "choices": {"A": " 6", "B": " 12", "C": " 18", "D": " 30", "E": " 36"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28.  Looking out his apartment window that is 20 feet above the ground and directly over the front door, Han could see a red flower on the sidewalk. As shown below, the angle formed by the building and Han's line of sight to the flower is 35\u00b0. Approximately how many feet from the front door is the flower?\uff08Note: tan 35\u00b0 \u2248 .70, cos 35\u00b0 \u2248 .82, sin 35\u00b0 \u2248 .57)", "choices": {"A": " 6", "B": " 8", "C": " 11", "D": " 14", "E": " 16"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29.  In the figure below, AB || DC, \u2220A measures 41\u00b0, \u2220C measures 110\u00b0, and \u2220ADB measures 122\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220CBD?", "choices": {"A": " 17\u00b0", "B": " 41\u00b0", "C": " 53\u00b0", "D": " 63\u00b0", "E": " 69\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30.  The coordinates of the endpoints of JK, in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, are(-2,-6) and (4,6). What is the x-coordinate of the midpoint of JK?", "choices": {"A": " 0", "B": " 1", "C": " 2", "D": " 3", "E": " 6"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. What is the exponent on a in the product 2ax \u00b7 a3 \u00b7 3ay?", "choices": {"A": " 6", "B": " 3 + x + y", "C": " 3 + xy", "D": " 3x + y", "E": " 3xy"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32.  For all x and y , x2y2 - 16 =?", "choices": {"A": " (xy - 16)(xy + 1)", "B": " (xy - 8)2", "C": " (xy - 8)(xy + 8)", "D": " (xy - 4)(xy + 4)", "E": " (xy - 4)2"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33.  A high school sells student tickets for a band concert for $2 each and nonstudent tickets for $4 each. How many student tickets did the high school sell if the high school sold 220 tickets worth a total of $640?", "choices": {"A": " 180", "B": " 120", "C": " 110", "D": " 100", "E": " 40"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34.  The trapezoid below, with dimensions given in inches, has an area of 36 square inches. What are the lengths ,in inches, of the bases of the trapezoid?\uff08Note:  is a formula for the area of a trapezoid.)", "choices": {"A": " 4 and 14", "B": " 6 and 9", "C": " 6 and 12", "D": " 8 and 10", "E": " 9 and 9"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35.  What is the value of x in the solution to the system of equations below?2x + y = 2a2x - y = 2b", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " a + b", "C": " a - b", "D": " -a + b", "E": " -a - b"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Every integer is in 1 and only 1 of the following sets:{\u00b7\u00b7\u00b7, -15, -10, -5, 0, 5, 10, 15, \u00b7\u00b7\u00b7}, denoted [0]{\u00b7\u00b7\u00b7, -14, -9, -4, 1, 6, 11, 16, \u00b7\u00b7\u00b7}, denoted [1]{\u00b7\u00b7\u00b7, -13, -8, -3, 2, 7, 12, 17, \u00b7\u00b7\u00b7}, denoted [2]{\u00b7\u00b7\u00b7, -12, -7, -2, 3, 8, 13, 18, \u00b7\u00b7\u00b7}, denoted [3]{\u00b7\u00b7\u00b7, -11, -6, -1, 4, 9, 14, 19, \u00b7\u00b7\u00b7}, denoted [4]The integer 239 is in which of these sets?", "choices": {"A": " [0]", "B": " [1]", "C": " [2]", "D": " [3]", "E": " [4]"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37.  The average density of an object is defined as the object's average weight per unit volume. A slab of building material is a rectangular solid that is 8 feet long, 2 feet wide, and  foot high. If the slab weighs 250 pounds, about what is its average density in pounds per cubic foot?", "choices": {"A": " 1,000", "B": " 62.5", "C": " 24.4", "D": " 0.041", "E": " 0.016"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38.  Consider two geometric sequences, denoted S1 and S2. S1 has 40 as its 1st term, and S2 has 100 as its 1st term. For both S1 and S2, each term after the 1st term is  of the term preceding it. Which term of S2 will have the same value as the 4th term of S1?", "choices": {"A": " 2nd", "B": " 3rd", "C": " 4th", "D": " 5th", "E": " 10th"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39.  In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, what is the perimeter, in coordinate units, of an isosceles triangle having vertices A(-2, -1), B(3, 11), and C(8, -1) ?", "choices": {"A": "23", "B": " 33", "C": " 36", "D": " 44", "E": " 55"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40.  In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, a circle with its center at (6,9) and a radius of 5 units has which of the following as its equation?", "choices": {"A": " (x - 6)2 + (y - 9)2 = 25", "B": " (x + 6)2 + (y + 9)2 = 25", "C": " (x + 6)2 + (y + 9)2 = 5", "D": " (x + 9)2 + (y + 6)2 = 25", "E": " (x - 9)2 + (y - 6)2 = 5"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41.  For all real x \u2260 0, ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42.  What is the area, in square units, of a circle that has a circumference 18\u03c0 units long?", "choices": {"A": " 9\u03c0", "B": " 18\u03c0", "C": " 36\u03c0", "D": " 81\u03c0", "E": " 324\u03c0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43.  If a ship continues on its current heading, it will hit a rock 3, 000 feet ahead at point X, as shown below. Which of the following equations will give the angle of the course correction needed so the ship will clear point X by 100 feet?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44.  What is the solution set for the equation |x - 1| = 2?", "choices": {"A": " The empty set", "B": " {3}", "C": " {-1, 1}", "D": " {-1, 3}", "E": " {-3, 3}"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45.  The line graphed in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below is also represented by one of the following equations. Which equation is it?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " y = 4x + 6"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46.  Which of the following is the graph of the region 1 &lt; x + y &lt; 2 in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47.  What is the difference between the mean and the median of the set (3, 8, 10, 15}?", "choices": {"A": " 0", "B": " 1", "C": " 4", "D": " 9", "E": " 12"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48.  Consider the following system of equations in x and y, where the values of m and n are NOT the same.ax + by = max + by = nIf you correctly graph this system, which of the following could be your graph?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49.  Given  and , what is ?", "choices": {"A": " -3", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " 0", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50.  Casey paid $8.56, which included sales tax of 7%, for a cassette. Which of the following, when solved, will give c, the before-tax price, in dollars, of the cassette?", "choices": {"A": " c + .07c = 8.56", "B": " c + .07(8.56) = 8.56", "C": " c + .07 = 8.56", "D": " c(c + .07) = 8.56", "E": " .07c = 8.56"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51.  For the rectangle below, with dimensions in feet, which of the following is an irrational number?", "choices": {"A": " The ratio of the width of the rectangle to its length", "B": " The product of the length and width of the rectangle", "C": " The percent of the rectangle that is below the diagonal", "D": " The perimeter of the rectangle", "E": " The length of the diagonal of the rectangle"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52.  In the figure below, AB and AC are tangent to the circle at B and C, respectively, and O is the center of the circle. If \u2220BAC measures 40\u00b0, how many degrees does \u2220AOB measure?", "choices": {"A": " 40\u00b0", "B": " 50\u00b0", "C": " 60\u00b0", "D": " 70\u00b0", "E": " 80\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. Pat sells refrigerators and is paid $200 per week plus125 commission for each refrigerator she sells. Which of the following is an expression for the number of refrigerators she would need to sell in a given week in order to earn a total of P dollars that week?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54.  When x represents an integer, the statement \"If x is divisible by 4, then x is even\" is equivalent to which of the statements below?I. If x is not divisible by 4, then x is not even.II. If x is even, then x is divisible by 4.III. If x is not even, then x is not divisible by 4.", "choices": {"A": "  I only", "B": " II only", "C": " III only", "D": " II and III only", "E": " I, II, and III"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55.  Which of the following number line graphs represents the solution set of the inequality 2x2 - 7x &gt;  4?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56.  A line in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane passes through the points (-1,3) and (1,k). If the slope of the line is 2, what is the value of k?", "choices": {"A": " -1", "B": " 1", "C": " 5", "D": " 6", "E": " 7"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57.  In right triangle \u0394ADE shown below, C is on AE, is on AD, and BC is parallel to DE. The dimensions given are in centimeters. How many centimeters long is BD?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " 3", "E": " 5"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58.  In the regular heptagon shown below, what is the sum of the measures of the 7 interior angles?", "choices": {"A": " 360\u00b0", "B": " 720\u00b0", "C": " 900\u00b0", "D": " 1,080\u00b0", "E": " 1,260\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59.  The following identities are true whenever x is an angle measure such that 0\u00b0 &lt; x &lt; 90\u00b0: sinx cscx=1, cosx secx = 1, and tanx cotx = 1. For x such that 0\u00b0 &lt; x &lt; 90\u00b0 and , what is the value of secx?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60.  If p is a positive real number and 2 sin x = 2 sin(x + p) for every real value of x, what is the smallest possible value for p, in degrees? ", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " 2\u00b0", "C": " 180\u00b0", "D": " 360\u00b0", "E": " 720\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}]}